<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- Red Varietal wines -->
    <string-array name="fact_red_wine_name">
        <item>Cabernet Sauvignon</item>
        <item>Cabernet Franc</item>
        <item>Merlot</item>
        <item>Pinot Noir</item>
        <item>Zinfandel</item>
        <item>Chianti</item>
        <item>Sangiovese</item>
        <item>Claret</item>
        <item>Malbec</item>
        <item>Petite Sirah</item>
        <item>Port</item>
        <item>Rose</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="cabernetsauvignon">Currant, Plum, Black Cherry and Spice, with notes of Olive,
        Vanilla Mint, Tobacco, Toasty Cedar, Anise, Pepper and Herbs. Full-bodied wines with great
        depth that improve with aging. Cabernet spends from 15 to 30 months aging in American and
        French Oak barrels which tend to soften the tannins, adding the toasty cedar and vanilla flavors.</string>

    <string name="cabernetfranc">Red wine grape used in Bordeaux for blending with Cabernet
        Sauvignon. It is an earlier-maturing red wine, due to its lower level of tannins.
        Light to medium-bodied wine with more immediate fruit than Cabernet Sauvignon and some of
        the herbaceous odors evident in unripe Cabernet Sauvignon.</string>

    <string name="merlot">Herbs, Green Olive, Cherry and Chocolate. Softer and medium in weight with
        fewer tannins than Cabernet and ready to drink sooner. Takes well to Oak aging. It is
        frequently used as a blending wine with Cabernet to soften</string>

    <string name="pinotnoir">This is the great, noble grape of Burgundy. Difficult to grow but at
        its best it is smooth and richer than Cabernet Sauvignon with less tannin. Raisin like
        flavors with undertones of black cherry, spice and raspberry. Widely used in the making of
        champagne sparkling wines.</string>

    <string name="zinfandel">With predominant raspberry flavors and a spicy aroma, Zinfandels can
        be bold and intense as well as light and fruity. It takes well to blending bringing out
        flavors of cherry, wild berry and plum with notes of leather, earth and tar. It is the most
        widely grown grape in California. Much of it is turned into White Zinfandel, a blush wine
        that is slightly sweet.</string>

    <string name="chianti">From a blend of grapes this fruity, light ruby-to-garnet-colored red may
        be called Chianti Riserva when aged three or more years</string>

    <string name="sangiovese">Known for its supple texture, medium to full-bodied spice flavors,
        raspberry cherry and anise. Sangiovese is used in many fine Italian wines including Chianti</string>

    <string name="claret">British term for red Bordeaux/Cabernet Sauvignon wines.</string>

    <string name="malbec">Once important in Bordeaux and the Loire in various blends,
        this not-very-hardy grape has been steadily replaced by Merlot and the two Cabernets.
        However, Argentina is markedly successful with this varietal. In the United States Malbec
        is a blending grape only, and an insignificant one at that, but a few wineries use it, the
        most obvious reason being that it’s considered part of the Bordeaux-blend recipe.</string>

    <string name="petitesirah">Plum and blackberry flavors mark this deep, ruby colored wine.
        Usually full-bodied with chewy tannins. Used in France and California as a blending wine.
        Not related to the Syrah of France</string>

    <string name="port">Fortified wine from the Douro region of Portugal. 
        Styles include: Late Bottle (LB), Tawny, Ruby, Aged, and Vintage. Mostly sweet and red</string>

    <string name="rose">Sometimes called blush. Any light pink wine, dry to sweet, made by
        removing the skins of red grapes early in the fermentation process or by mixing red and white</string>


</resources>